{"1": {"question": "What genre is Fr\u00c3\u00bchlingstraum?", "correct": "A Romantic Lied (German art song)", "incorrect": ["An English art song", "A romantic art song", "Jazz", "Rock"]}, "2": {"question": "What are the main keys used in Fr\u00c3\u00bchlingstraum?", "correct": "F Major and F Minor", "incorrect": ["E Major and E minor", "G Major, G minor and D minor", "C Major and G minor", "F Major and C Major"]}, "3": {"question": "Why was Fr\u00c3\u00bchlingstraum transposed from A major and A minor to F Major and F Minor?", "correct": "To suit a lower voice. ", "incorrect": ["To make it easier to play.", "Because Schubert felt like it.", "Because no-one liked the key of the song.", "Because Schubert got sick of the original key."]}, "4": {"question": "What does Fr\u00c3\u00bchlingstraum mean?", "correct": "Spring dream or Dream of Spring", "incorrect": ["Spring Journey", "Blossoming Flowers", "Spring Breeze", "Has no particular translation to English"]}, "5": {"question": "What is the form of Fr\u00c3\u00bchlingstraum?", "correct": "A slightly modified version of strophic form.", "incorrect": ["Modified Strophic form", "Through Composed Form", "Binary Form", "Sonata Form"]}, "6": {"question": "What does 'Etwas bewegt' mean?", "correct": "Moving along (similar to Con Moto)", "incorrect": ["Previous Tempo", "Slow and Gentle", "Extremely Fast", "Powerful and Loud"]}, "7": {"question": "What does 'Schnell' mean?", "correct": "Fast", "incorrect": ["Raw Chicken", "Suddenly Play softly", "Moderately Slow", "Gradually increase in volume"]}, "8": {"question": "What does 'Langsam' mean?", "correct": "Slow", "incorrect": ["Very Soft", "Moderately light ", "Play very Smoothly", "Moderately Slow"]}, "9": {"question": "Who wrote the source material that Schubert used for 'Fr\u00c3\u00bchlingstraum'?", "correct": "Wilhelm M\u00c3\u00bcller", "incorrect": ["Bach", "George Handel", "Schumann", "William Shakespeare"]}, "10": {"question": "Which other keys are briefly used in Fr\u00c3\u00bchlingstraum?", "correct": "C minor, B flat major and E flat minor", "incorrect": ["G minor and A Minor", "Just B Major", "C# Minor and G# major", "C Major, G major and A Major"]}, "11": {"question": "What movement # is Fr\u00c3\u00bchlingstraum (within the larger work it is a part of)?", "correct": "11", "incorrect": ["12", "16", "14", "10"]}, "12": {"question": "What larger work is Fr\u00c3\u00bchlingstraum from?", "correct": "Winterreise", "incorrect": ["Die sch\u00c3\u00b6ne M\u00c3\u00bcllerin", "Dichterliebe", "Kindertotenlieder", "Liederkreis, Op. 39"]}, "13": {"question": "What type of work is the larger work that Fr\u00c3\u00bchlingstraum is from?", "correct": "Lieder", "incorrect": ["Art song", "Pop", "Blues", "Country Music"]}, "14": {"question": "What does Winterreise mean in English?", "correct": "Winter Journey", "incorrect": ["Winter Nights", "Winter Life", "Cold Winters", "Sad Winter"]}, "15": {"question": "Which Two Stanzas in Fr\u00c3\u00bchlingstraum change to 2/4?", "correct": "Stanzas 3 and 6", "incorrect": ["Stanzas 1 and 2", "Stanzas 1 and 4", "Stanzas 2 and 5", "No stanzas have a time signature of 2/4"]}, "16": {"question": "What is a Lied?", "correct": "German art song", "incorrect": ["Trumpian Rhetoric", "Art song in English", "How you stop a dog from running away", "A German folk song for 2 voices"]}, "17": {"question": "What language is Fr\u00c3\u00bchlingstraum in?", "correct": "German", "incorrect": ["Dutch", "Latin", "French", "Spanish"]}, "18": {"question": "Which poet has had the most Lieder set to their text?", "correct": "Goethe", "incorrect": ["Mozart", "Shakespeare", "Schubert", "Wilhelm M\u00c3\u00bcller"]}, "19": {"question": "When was the Lied developed?", "correct": "Late 18th Century", "incorrect": ["Late 1800s", "Early 18th Century", "Early 1800s", "Last year"]}, "20": {"question": "Where did Schubert live?", "correct": "Vienna, Austria", "incorrect": ["Vienna, Australia", "Salzburg, Austria", "Munich, Germany", "London, UK"]}, "21": {"question": "When was Winterreise composed?", "correct": "1828", "incorrect": ["1868", "1768", "2028", "Trick question, it wasn't composed!"]}, "22": {"question": "Who was the first composer to link multiple Lieder together into a coherent cycle?", "correct": "Beethoven", "incorrect": ["Schubert", "Mozart", "Finzi", "Bach"]}, "23": {"question": "What did the development of a song cycle allow composers to do?", "correct": "Explore larger themes and ideas over a greater span of time and with more dramatic development.", "incorrect": ["Put songs in a certain order", "Sort their songs into smaller parts to make it easier for people to learn", "To show the audience their favourite songs in order"]}, "24": {"question": "What are individual lieder put together into cycles called?", "correct": "Liederkreis", "incorrect": ["Lieder cycle", "Liedergroup", "Song cycle"]}, "25": {"question": "What is the name of Beethoven's first Liederkreis?", "correct": "An die ferne Geliebte, Op. 98", "incorrect": ["He didn't compose any", "Dichterliebe, Op. 48", "Liederkreis, Op. 24"]}, "26": {"question": "What does 'Wie Oben' mean?", "correct": "As above, to play the above tempo", "incorrect": ["Play original tempo", "As above, to play the above dynamics", "Gradually increase in tempo"]}, "27": {"question": "What is 'ligato'?", "correct": "An alternate spelling of legato", "incorrect": ["An incorrect spelling of legato", "It means to play freely", "To come to a sudden stop"]}, "28": {"question": "What does 'legato' mean?", "correct": "Smooth and connected", "incorrect": ["Cooked Chicken legs", "To play loud and strongly", "Decrease in dynamic until it is the same as the piano's"]}, "29": {"question": "What does lied mean?", "correct": "Song in German", "incorrect": ["Tempo ", "The past tense of telling a false statement", "To suddenly increase in dynamic (translated from Italian)", "A strap or chain used to tether a pet while walking them."]}, "30": {"question": "How far do songs with German texts go back?", "correct": "The middle ages", "incorrect": ["World war 1", "The 1800s", "1999", "Approximately 8 metres"]}, "31": {"question": "How many lieder did Schubert compose in his career?", "correct": "Over 600", "incorrect": ["356", "No-one kept track of how many he wrote", "Only 5"]}, "32": {"question": "How old was Schubert when he composed Winterreise?", "correct": "~31 years old", "incorrect": ["16 Years old", "42", "The exact year when Schubert wrote Winterreise is still unknown"]}, "33": {"question": "An important factor in the development of the Romantic Lied was the growing availability and popularity of what?", "correct": "The Piano", "incorrect": ["Uranium", "Manuscript paper", "Voices", "Formal music training"]}, "34": {"question": "When was Schubert alive?", "correct": "1797-1828", "incorrect": ["1787-1828", "1828-1797 BCE", "       1797-1892"]}, "35": {"question": "Which part of Schubert's lifetime was Winterreise composed?", "correct": "Near the end", "incorrect": ["Roughly halfway through", "No one knew, he composed this Liederkreis secretly", "In his teen years"]}, "36": {"question": "What is a lied?", "correct": "A song set to a German Text", "incorrect": ["A song set to English text", "The beginning of a musical section", "A song with two parts"]}, "37": {"question": "Which century did lied gain widepread recognition as a high art form?", "correct": "19th Century", "incorrect": ["2nd April, 1851", "18th Century", "21st Century", "29th Century"]}, "38": {"question": "Who developed the idea that language was the most significant determinant of social cohesion?", "correct": "Johann Gottfried Herder", "incorrect": ["Henry Purcell", "Benjamin Britten", "Ralph Vaugn Williams", "Beethoven"]}, "39": {"question": "German lied were produced in significant numbers for what?", "correct": "Domestic Consumption", "incorrect": []}, "40": {"question": "What are iambs?", "correct": "Two syllables in unstressed-stressed configuration", "incorrect": ["Meat from a sheep"]}, "41": {"question": "What is an amphibrach?", "correct": "Unstressed-stressed-unstressed configuration", "incorrect": ["A type of animal", " "]}, "42": {"question": "How long did Schubert live in the capital of Austria?", "correct": "His whole life", "incorrect": ["For 12 years", "The first half of his life", "He never did", "29 years"]}, "43": {"question": "Schubert's Gretchen am Spinnrade (Gretchen at the Spinning Wheel) Op. 22 D 118 stood out as what?", "correct": "A milestone in the evolution in the genre (lied)", "incorrect": ["One of the worst representations of the lied genre."]}, "44": {"question": "How many bars does the piano introduction at the beginning Fr\u00c3\u00bchlingstraum last for?", "correct": "4 Bars", "incorrect": ["12 bars", "8 bars", "6 bars", "32 bars"]}, "45": {"question": "What does 'Singstimme' mean?", "correct": "Voice", "incorrect": ["Time to sing", "Piano"]}, "46": {"question": "What is the main time signature of Fr\u00c3\u00bchlingstraum?", "correct": "6/8", "incorrect": ["3/4", "3/8", "9/8"]}, "47": {"question": "When during the piece does the key signature change?", "correct": "It doesn't change at all", "incorrect": ["Development", "Recapitulation", "Section B"]}, "48": {"question": "What is the stanza pattern for Fr\u00c3\u00bchlingstraum?", "correct": "abcabc", "incorrect": ["ababc", "aabbabc", "aabbcc"]}, "49": {"question": "Winterreise was widely acknowledged as being what?", "correct": "One of the greatest masterpieces of the early Romantic German lied.", "incorrect": []}, "50": {"question": "What was the significance of Beethoven's An die ferne Geliebte (To the distant beloved), Op. 98 (1816)?", "correct": "It was the very first Liederkreis ever put together.", "incorrect": ["It inspired many other composers of the time to give their songs an Op. #", "It was the very first composition to have a German name"]}, "51": {"question": "What is the plural form of lied?", "correct": "Lieder", "incorrect": ["Lieding", "Lieds", "Lieders"]}, "52": {"question": "One important factor in the development of lied was the growth of German as what?", "correct": "A literary language", "incorrect": ["A country", "A nationality"]}, "53": {"question": "What are melismas?", "correct": "A group of notes sung to one syllable", "incorrect": ["A group of notes sung with different note values but with the same pitch", "A group of notes sung all slurred", "A group of notes sung staccato"]}, "54": {"question": "What are quatrains?", "correct": "A stanza of four lines", "incorrect": ["Tenor Saxophonists", "A group of four people", "A train with four carriages"]}, "55": {"question": "How many quatrains does Fr\u00c3\u00bchingstraum contain?", "correct": "6", "incorrect": ["4", "8", "12"]}, "56": {"question": "What does the K in K387 stand for?", "correct": "K\u00c3\u00b6chel", "incorrect": ["Keldorfer", "Kreisler", "Krenek"]}, "57": {"question": "What is the form of 1st movement of string quartet K. 387?", "correct": "Sonata Form", "incorrect": ["Ternary form", "Rondo Form", "Binary form"]}, "58": {"question": "What is the main Key of the 1st movement of String Quartet K. 387?", "correct": "G Major", "incorrect": ["D Major", "G minor", "F Major"]}, "59": {"question": "When did string quartets first appear?", "correct": "1760s", "incorrect": ["1734", "1670s", "1890s"]}, "60": {"question": "What instrument or instruments start the second subject of the exposition in Mozart's String Quartet in G Major, K. 387, 1st Movement?", "correct": "2nd Violin", "incorrect": ["1st Violin and 2nd Violin", "1st violin and Cello", "Viola"]}, "61": {"question": "Who did Mozart dedicate his String Quartet K. 387 to?", "correct": "Joseph Haydn", "incorrect": ["Franz Schubert", "George Frederic Handel", "Johann Hummell"]}, "62": {"question": "What larger work is String Quartet K. 387 by Mozart part of?", "correct": "The \"Hayden Quartets\"", "incorrect": ["The \"Viennese Quartets\"", "Milanese Quartets", "Prussian Quartets"]}, "63": {"question": "How many movements are in String Quartet K. 387 by Mozart?", "correct": "Four", "incorrect": ["Five", "Three", "Six"]}, "64": {"question": "What does 'allegro vivace assai'  mean?", "correct": "Fast and very lively", "incorrect": ["Fast and smooth", "Moderately fast", "Extremely fast and gentle"]}, "65": {"question": "What is the main key of the 1st movement of String Quartet K. 387 by Mozart?", "correct": "G Major", "incorrect": ["D Major", "E Minor", "C Major"]}, "66": {"question": "Which instrument/s plays the main part in the 1st movement of String Quartet K. 387?", "correct": "1st Violin", "incorrect": ["There is no main part - each part has an equal role", "Viola", "1st and 2nd violin"]}, "67": {"question": "Where was Mozart's String Quartet K. 387 composed?", "correct": "Vienna", "incorrect": ["Salzberg", "Innsbruck", "Graz"]}, "68": {"question": "How many String Quartets did Mozart dedicate to Hayden?", "correct": "6", "incorrect": ["4", "8", "2"]}, "69": {"question": "What type of Cadence does the Exposition of the 1st Movement of Mozart's K. 387 end on?", "correct": "Perfect Cadence", "incorrect": ["Interrupted", "Imperfect", "Plagal"]}, "70": {"question": "What order # is String Quartet K. 387 in its larger work?", "correct": "1st", "incorrect": ["6th (Last)", "2nd", "5th"]}, "71": {"question": "How many different clefs are used in Mozart K. 387 mvt 1?", "correct": "3", "incorrect": ["2", "Only 1", "4"]}, "72": {"question": "What is the instrumentation for Mozart's 1st Movement of String Quartet K. 387?", "correct": "Violin 1, Violin 2, Viola, and Cello", "incorrect": ["Violin, Viola, Cello, Double Bass", "Piano and voice", "Violin 1, Violin 2 and Cello", "Piano, Violin, Viola, Cello"]}, "73": {"question": "How many instrumental parts are in 1st Movement of String Quartet K. 387?", "correct": "4", "incorrect": ["5", "3", "6"]}, "74": {"question": "What is the standard instrumentation of the String quartet?", "correct": "Violin 1, Violin 2, Viola, and Cello", "incorrect": ["Violin, Cello 1, Cello 2, and Double Bass", "Violin, Viola, Cello, and Double Bass", "Violin, Viola 1, Viola 2, and Double Bass"]}, "75": {"question": "What was the time span of the classical period?", "correct": "c. 1750 - 1800", "incorrect": ["c. 1700 - 1800", "c. 1650 - 1800", "c. 1500 - 1600"]}, "76": {"question": "What are the main sections in sonata form?", "correct": "Exposition, Development and Recapitulation", "incorrect": ["Beginning, middle and end", "Introduction, Interlude and Exposition", "Exposition, Interlude and Recapitulation "]}, "77": {"question": "When were the Haydn Quartets composed?", "correct": "1782 - 1785", "incorrect": ["1762 - 1770", "2020 - 2022", "1723 - 1725"]}, "78": {"question": "Where were the Haydn Quartets composed?", "correct": "Vienna, Austria", "incorrect": ["London, England", "New York, USA", "Sydney, Australia"]}, "79": {"question": "When did Haydn himself listen to the 6 Haydn Quartets?", "correct": "In 1785", "incorrect": ["In 1775", "In 1995", "In 1786", "Tomorrow"]}, "80": {"question": "What were the Haydn Quartets composed in response to?", "correct": "Haydn - Op. 33 set", "incorrect": ["Haydn - Cello Concerto No. 1", "Haydn - Trumpet Concerto", "Haydn - Symphony No. 94"]}, "81": {"question": " At the time of the development of the String Quartet, what did it provide to wealthy individuals and families?", "correct": "Opportunities for private entertainment", "incorrect": ["Free performances", "Better performers to listen to than in normal public concerts", "More inspiration for them to write songs"]}, "82": {"question": "Why were string quartet performances suitable for private entertainment?", "correct": "It only requires 4 players and a small space for them to play in.", "incorrect": ["Many people played in String Quartets at the time, which meant that many people could recieve private entertainment", "String Quartet Performances were very short which meant it was cheap for private entertainment ", "1 person could play all four parts at once so you only needed to hire one person to play"]}, "83": {"question": "What is the piece format of a typical string quartet?", "correct": "Fast movement, Slow Movement, Minuet and trio and the Fast Finale", "incorrect": ["Minuet and Trio, Slow Movement, Fast Movement and Fast Finale", "Introduction, Fast Movement, Slow Movement and Fast Finale", "There is not a typical Structure for a four movement piece"]}, "84": {"question": "What opportunity did String Quartets give composers?", "correct": "A great range of expressive possibilities", "incorrect": ["To make more money as writing String Quartet pieces were easy to compose", "An opportunity to become famous", "To make music that sounded like rock music"]}, "85": {"question": "Where did string quartets first appear?", "correct": "Southern Germany, Austria and Bohemia", "incorrect": ["England", "Slovakia", "Western Russia"]}, "86": {"question": "By about when had the String Quartet been consolidated into its classical format?", "correct": "About 1780", "incorrect": ["1995", "2020", "1770"]}, "87": {"question": "What was Mozart's father's name?", "correct": "Leopold", "incorrect": ["Gerald", "Frederick", "Johann"]}, "88": {"question": "Who said 'Before God, and as an honest man, I tell you that your son is the greatest composer known to me either in person or by name.' to Mozart's Father, Leopold?", "correct": "Haydn", "incorrect": ["Hummel", "Mozart", "Himself"]}, "89": {"question": "Where was Mozart's father, Leopold, at the time Haydn heard the Haydn quartets?", "correct": "Salzburg", "incorrect": ["Finland", "Rome", "Munich"]}, "90": {"question": "How many main sections are there in sonata form?", "correct": "3", "incorrect": ["4", "2", "6"]}, "91": {"question": "What does op. mean?", "correct": "Opus", "incorrect": ["Over powered", "Operation", "Original piece"]}, "92": {"question": "What op. number did Mozart publish the Haydn Quartets as?", "correct": "Op. 10", "incorrect": ["Op. 11", "Op. 4", "Op. 103"]}, "93": {"question": "What is the general role of the development section?", "correct": "To modulate through a range of keys, while eventually working its way back to the tonic key.", "incorrect": ["To entertain the audience using a variety of note values", "To establish the general mood of the piece"]}, "94": {"question": "What is a subordinate theme?", "correct": "It is the ending of a section or part.", "incorrect": ["A theme within a theme", "A short phrase that is played in another key signature", "The part leading up to the climax of the piece"]}, "95": {"question": "How many players are there in a String Quartet?", "correct": "4", "incorrect": ["6", "5", "2"]}, "96": {"question": "What is a large-scale instrumental genre?", "correct": "A genre that requires a large number of people to play.", "incorrect": ["A genre that requires people to play extrememly large instruments.", "A genre that often includes practise scales in its music.", "A genre in which its musical pieces are of a long duration"]}, "97": {"question": "What phrase can you use to refer to more than one subordinate theme?", "correct": "A Subordinate theme group", "incorrect": ["Subordinate themes", "Subordinate theme cycle", "Sub-cycle"]}, "98": {"question": "The cello can use multiple clefs, but which clef does it use in Mozart's 1st Movement of String Quartet K. 387?", "correct": "Bass Clef", "incorrect": ["Tenor Clef", "Alto clef", "Treble Clef"]}, "99": {"question": "What is the time signature in the 1st Movement of String Quartet K. 387 by Mozart?", "correct": "4/4", "incorrect": ["2/2", "6/4", "3/2"]}, "100": {"question": "What are codettas?", "correct": "A series of cadence-like gestures.", "incorrect": ["The symbol used on sheet music that show you need to go to the coda", "Codetta bake shop (there's one in the US)", "Sheet music symbols that indicate a composition for two performers"]}, "101": {"question": "In Mozart's 1st movement of String Quartet K. 387, only one instrument/part plays in the anacrusis. Which instrument/part is this?", "correct": " Violin 1", "incorrect": ["Cello", "Double Bass", "Violin 2"]}, "102": {"question": "What is an Antecedent phrase?", "correct": "A Phrase, usually 4 bars, that precedes the consequent phrase.", "incorrect": ["The phrase that leads into the next section of the piece.", "It is a phrase that is repeated throughout the piece", "A phrase that modulates to another key for a short period of time"]}, "103": {"question": "What are the two different variations of the exposition that could be used in the recapitulation called?", "correct": "Decorative and Structural", "incorrect": ["Sarabande and Minuet", "Decorative and Formal", "Structural and Minuet"]}, "104": {"question": "How many quartets in the set of 6 by Haydn (as Op. 33 in 1781) follow the typical classical format of a piece in four movements?", "correct": "All of them", "incorrect": ["2", "None. The format didn't exist when the quartets were published.", "Only the First and Last"]}, "105": {"question": "Haydn's Op. 33, the set of six quartets, are often reffered to as what?", "correct": "The 'Russian' quartets", "incorrect": ["The Royal Quartets", "The Grand Quartets", "It wasn't reffered as to anything."]}, "106": {"question": "Who did Haydn dedicate his Op. 33 set to?", "correct": "The Grand Duke Paul of Russia", "incorrect": ["Mozart", "Schumann", "Schubert"]}, "107": {"question": "First subject' and 'Second subject', or 'primary theme' and 'secondary theme' are other names for what?", "correct": "The 'Main theme' and 'subordinate theme' in Sonata Form.", "incorrect": ["Main theme', and 'antecedent' and 'consequent' phrase", "The Development section", "A phrase that modulates to another key for a short period of time"]}, "108": {"question": "What is a sequence?", "correct": "A passage repeated at a higher or lower pitch.", "incorrect": ["A passage repeated at the same pitch", "A passage repeated at the same pitch, but using different note values", "A passage repeated using randomised pitches"]}, "109": {"question": "Typically, how many bars do antecedent and consequent phrases each last for?", "correct": "4 bars each", "incorrect": ["6 bars", "3 bars", "2 bars"]}, "110": {"question": "What is the genre of O mistress mine?", "correct": "20th Century English Art Song", "incorrect": ["20th Century Leider", "Pop", "19th Century Lieder", "19th Century English Art Song", "Jazz"]}, "111": {"question": "What does 'Allegretto amabile' mean?", "correct": "Moderately fast, and amiable (pleasant or charming)", "incorrect": ["Really fast and amiable", "Slow", "Play moderately fast on every second bar", "Quickly increase volume", "Quickly drop in Volume"]}, "112": {"question": "What does 'sempre staccato' mean?", "correct": "Always detached", "incorrect": ["Very detached", "Suddenly detached", "Always stuck", "Moderately detached", "Detachted every second note"]}, "113": {"question": "What is the form of O Mistress Mine, by Finzi?", "correct": "Modified Strophic Form", "incorrect": ["Rondo form", "Strophic Form", "Ternary form", "Through composed form", "Binary Form"]}, "114": {"question": "Which keys are used in O mistress mine?", "correct": "Eb Major and Eb Minor", "incorrect": ["G Major only", "E Major and E minor", "D Major and A major ", "C Major and G Minor", "F Major and F Minor"]}, "115": {"question": "What does 'rinforzando subito' mean?", "correct": "Sudddenly reinforce or emphasise", "incorrect": ["Suddenly get louder", "Suddenly get louder, then gradually get softer.", "Suddenly get softer", "Suddenly increase tempo", "Immediately become more gentle"]}, "116": {"question": "How many sections are there in O mistress mine?", "correct": "5", "incorrect": ["7", "4", "6", "9", "2"]}, "117": {"question": "What is the order of the sections in O mistress mine?", "correct": "The introduction, Stanza 1, Interlude, Stanza 2, Postlude.", "incorrect": ["Introduction, Stanza 1, Interlude and Stanza 2.", "Stanza 1, Stanza 2 and Postlude", "Introduction, Stanza 1 and Stanza 2", "Introduction, Stanza 1 and Postlude", "Stanza 1 and Stanza 2"]}, "118": {"question": "In O mistress mine, what is the mood/feeling of the major key sections?", "correct": "Bright and Jaunty", "incorrect": ["Sad and lonely", "Depressing", "Meh", "Calm", "Quick and Uptight"]}, "119": {"question": "What is the underlying message of the song?", "correct": "To seize life's joys and pleasures while you can", "incorrect": ["Only do what you want to do.", "Expect to have unfortunate things in your life.", "There is no message", "Stay on your phone the whole day", "Work hard you will be rewarded"]}, "120": {"question": "Who wrote the source material that Finzi used for O Mistress Mine?", "correct": "William Shakespeare", "incorrect": ["Wilhelm M\u00c3\u00bcller", "Michael", "George Handel", "Wilhelm Shakespeare", "Gerald Finzi"]}, "121": {"question": "Which sections in O mistress mine change to Eb Minor?", "correct": "Stanza 1 and Stanza 2", "incorrect": ["Introduction, Interlude and Postlude", "Only the Introduction", "Interlude and Postlude", "Introduction and Postlude ", "None"]}, "122": {"question": "What movement # is O Mistress Mine (within the larger work it is a part of)?\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t", "correct": "Fourth", "incorrect": ["Fifth", "First", "Second", "Not Part of a larger work at all", "Third"]}, "123": {"question": "What larger work is O Mistress Mine from?\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t", "correct": "Let us Garlands Bring", "incorrect": ["Winterreise", "Songs of Travel", "Liederkreis", "Dichterliebe", "Die sch\u00c3\u00b6ne M\u00c3\u00bcllerin"]}, "124": {"question": "What type of work is the larger work that O Mistress Mine is from?", "correct": "Art Song", "incorrect": ["Lieder", "Opera", "Folk Music", "Blues", "Country Music"]}, "125": {"question": "What play is the lyrics for O Mistress Mine from?", "correct": "Twelfth Night", "incorrect": ["Macbeth", "Romeo and Juliet", "Othello", "Midsummer Night's Dream", "King Lear"]}, "126": {"question": "What is the rhyme scheme for each stanza in O mistress mine?", "correct": "aabccb", "incorrect": ["abac", "aba", "ab", "aabbccaa", "abca"]}, "127": {"question": "What is the instrumentation for O Mistress mine?", "correct": "Voice and piano", "incorrect": ["Typical String Quartet - 2 Violins, a Viola and a Cello", "2 Violins", "Violin and Piano", "Trumpet and Piano", "Piano only"]}, "128": {"question": "What dynamic does O mistress mine begin on?", "correct": "mf", "incorrect": ["f ", "p", "a bit louder than mp", "fff", "There is no dynamic marking"]}, "129": {"question": "What is the name of a six-line stanza?", "correct": "sextain", "incorrect": ["sixtain", "six-line stanza", "sextillion", "quintain", "septet"]}, "130": {"question": "What is the cause of the presence of Cb, Db and Gb in O mistress mine?", "correct": "Modal Mixture", "incorrect": ["An unintended mistake by Finzi", "The notes used to be part of the key O mistress mine uses but then was changed", "A key change in the piece", "Some person sabotaged the sheet music and added flats randomly", "It was a trend at the time to add random notes to compositions"]}, "131": {"question": "What type of articulation is used to play the left hand in O mistress Mine?", "correct": "Staccato", "incorrect": ["Accents", "Tenutos", "Legato", "marcatos", "staccatissimo"]}, "132": {"question": "What does 'A Tempo' mean?", "correct": "Return to original speed", "incorrect": ["Literally just means \"A tempo\"", "Play a random tempo", "Gradually slow down and come to a stop", "Stay at the current tempo", "Play freely and ignore all past tempo markings"]}, "133": {"question": "What does senza rall mean?", "correct": "Without slowing down", "incorrect": ["Sneeze roll", "Slowly deacrease in dynamic", "slowly deacrease in tempo", "Without speeding up", "Gently and Gradually slow down "]}, "134": {"question": "What does 'lunga' mean?", "correct": "Long pause", "incorrect": ["Long phrasing", "Get down and do 10 Lunges!", "Lower your dynamic level", "Return to original speed slowly", "An alternate spelling of \"longer\""]}, "135": {"question": "When was 'Let us garlands bring' composed?", "correct": "1942", "incorrect": ["1952", "1924", "1842", "2023", "1130"]}, "136": {"question": "How many song cycles did Finzi compose?", "correct": "At least 8", "incorrect": ["12", "He didn't compose any song cycles -  he disliked them very much.", "9", "18", "4"]}, "137": {"question": "When did English art songs start to emerge?", "correct": "The late sixteenth century", "incorrect": ["2nd century", "100 BCE", "1700's", "1892", "Unknown", "The late 1600s"]}, "138": {"question": "Who composed the instrumentation to O mistress mine?", "correct": "Gerald Finzi", "incorrect": ["William Shakespeare", "Mozart", "Schubert", "Wilhelm M\u00c3\u00bcller", "Beethoven"]}, "139": {"question": "What does 'Molto' mean?", "correct": "much, very", "incorrect": ["Molten Rock", "Translates to \"Motor\" - Gradually Speed up", "Play very gently", "Play as loudly as you think is necessary", "Extremely soft "]}, "140": {"question": "What does 'Cantabile' mean?", "correct": "In a singing matter", "incorrect": ["much, very", "In a sad tone", "Without Slowing down", "It is the marking for a new stanza", "Freely"]}, "141": {"question": "In Shakespeare's Twelfth Night, who sings O mistress mine?", "correct": "Feste, a clown.", "incorrect": ["Malvolio", "Duke Orsino", "Maria", "No one does - the script writer couldn't decide", "Fabian"]}, "142": {"question": "What does 'Modal Mixture' mean?", "correct": "the use of chords belonging to a parallel key", "incorrect": ["The Mixture of Time Signatures", "the use of random tempos", "experiment with a variety of keys", "The adding of tone to a piece", "A variety of note lengths"]}, "143": {"question": "When was the \"English musical Renaissance\"?", "correct": "1890-1900", "incorrect": ["1790-1800", "1990-2000", "2190-2200", "Porridge", "It actually never happened"]}, "144": {"question": "What was the English art song increasingly dominated by during its development?", "correct": "The German lied", "incorrect": ["The war that was occuring at the time", "Emerging musicians who had no idea how to compose art song", "ACDC", "Irish folk songs", "Jazz"]}, "145": {"question": "What led to the 'English musical Renaissance'", "correct": "The folk-song revival movement", "incorrect": ["Finzi's creativity", "The first ever Rock and Roll record", "The first German Lied", "The first record company", "The end of ragtime music"]}, "146": {"question": "Ralf Vaughn Williams, John Ireland and Arnold Bax were all what?", "correct": "Significant English composers of the twentieth century", "incorrect": ["Minor English composers of the twentieth century", "Significant composers of lied", "Significant poets of the twentieth century", "Significant English composers of the nineteenth century", "German people"]}, "147": {"question": "When in Shakespeare's play Twelfth Night is O mistress mine sung?", "correct": "Act 2, Scene 3", "incorrect": ["Act 3, Scene 2", "Act 2, Scene 2", "Act 6, Scene 4", "Act 2, Scene 4", "At the end"]}, "148": {"question": "Footpath and Stile was Finzi's first song cycle, but what was Let us garlands bring?", "correct": "Finzi's third last", "incorrect": ["Finzi's thirteenth", "Shakespeares' last", "Schubert's third last", "Finzi's second last", "Finzi's Last"]}, "149": {"question": "Finzi's compositional efforts were particularly centred on what?", "correct": "Vocal music", "incorrect": ["tenor clef", "Piano Accompaniment", "String music", "Rock Music", "String Quartets"]}, "150": {"question": "The end of each stanza, the cadence leads into what?", "correct": "The next piano section", "incorrect": ["A short instrumental break", "The next stanza"]}, "151": {"question": "What happens in the final two lines in each stanza?", "correct": "A change of mood", "incorrect": []}, "152": {"question": "Between which years was Finzi alive?", "correct": "1901 - 1956", "incorrect": []}, "153": {"question": "What genre is Twelfth Night?", "correct": "Comedy", "incorrect": []}, "154": {"question": "What do the beginning and ending of each section in O Mistress Mine have in common?", "correct": "Similar music", "incorrect": []}, "155": {"question": "What does ritard. poco mean?", "correct": "Gradually slow down a little", "incorrect": []}, "156": {"question": "What is the given tempo marking for O Mistress Mine?", "correct": "Allegretto amabile", "incorrect": []}, "157": {"question": "What is the precise tempo marked for O Mistress Mine on the score?", "correct": "Minim = about 84 bpm", "incorrect": []}, "158": {"question": "Which sections in O Mistress mine have a time signature change?", "correct": "Stanza 1 and 2", "incorrect": []}, "159": {"question": "What time signature(s) does O Mistress Mine use?", "correct": "2/2 and 3/2", "incorrect": []}, "160": {"question": "What is a song cycle?", "correct": "A set of songs composed to be played in a certain sequence", "incorrect": []}, "161": {"question": "How many seperate texts by Shakespeare are used in Let us Garlands Bring?", "correct": "5", "incorrect": []}, "162": {"question": "What was one of the most common things between Art Song Composers?", "correct": "They turned to putting their music to important English Poets' text", "incorrect": []}, "163": {"question": "Shakespeare, Milton, Wordsworth, Coleridge and Hardy are all what?", "correct": "Important English Poets", "incorrect": []}, "164": {"question": "What is 5-1?", "correct": "4", "incorrect": ["(please replace this question, I'm just making it 55)"]}, "165": {"question": "What was the lied heavily influenced by?", "correct": "Poetry", "incorrect": ["Lead", "The peppa pig theme song", "Musicals"]}, "166": {"question": "When was the lied a very significant part of music?", "correct": "In the 18th and 19th Century", "incorrect": ["20th Century", "17th Century", "2013"]}, "167": {"question": "How many lieder did Schubert write?", "correct": "Over 600", "incorrect": ["212", "Over 800", "413"]}, "168": {"question": "In lieder and art song, when are the poems (words) written?", "correct": "Before the music is written", "incorrect": ["Whenever the poet feels like it", "After the music is written", "At the same time as the music"]}, "169": {"question": "In lieder and art song, the piano accompaniment is of what as the vocal line?", "correct": "Equal importance", "incorrect": ["Less importance", "More importance", "Nothing"]}, "170": {"question": "In lieder and art song, what does the piano part attempt to do?", "correct": "Describe what is happening in the poem", "incorrect": ["Add rhythmic interest", "Make the piano part sound strange", "Add melodic interest"]}, "171": {"question": "What is the German word for 'song'?", "correct": "Lieder", "incorrect": ["Sung", "Chanson", "Canzone"]}, "172": {"question": "What instrumentation is art song written for?", "correct": "Solo voice and piano", "incorrect": ["2 Violins, Viola and Cello", "Solo Voice", "Piano"]}, "173": {"question": "Which of the following forms is often used in lied and art song?", "correct": "Modified Strophic Form", "incorrect": ["Through composed form", "Sonata Form", "Ternary form"]}, "174": {"question": "Which form consists of repeated sections of the music that are varied or elaborated forms of the basic theme?", "correct": "Modified Strophic Form", "incorrect": ["Binary Form", "Strophic Form", "Rondo Form"]}, "175": {"question": "Which form has new music in each stanza?", "correct": "Through-composed form", "incorrect": ["Strophic Form", "Ternary form", "Through composed form"]}, "176": {"question": "What is the smallest to largest instrument in the orchestral string family?", "correct": "Violin, Viola, Cello, Double Bass", "incorrect": ["Viola, Violin, Cello, Double Bass", "Double Bass, Cello, Viola, Violin", "Cello, Violin, Double Bass, Viola"]}, "177": {"question": "What is a colloquial name for the violin?", "correct": "The fiddle", "incorrect": ["Licorice Stick", "Thermometer", "Box"]}, "178": {"question": "How much lower is the viola tuned than the violin?", "correct": "A fifth", "incorrect": ["A fourth", "A sixth", "A third"]}, "179": {"question": "Which clef does the viola primarily use?", "correct": "The alto clef", "incorrect": ["The tenor clef", "The treble clef", "The bass clef"]}, "180": {"question": "What are the 3 clefs that the cello uses?", "correct": "Treble, tenor and bass", "incorrect": ["Alto, tenor and Bass", "Treble, alto and Bass", "Treble, Alto and tenor"]}, "181": {"question": "Which is the only stringed instrument that is tuned in fourths?", "correct": "The Double Bass", "incorrect": ["The viola", "The guitar", "The violin"]}, "182": {"question": "How much lower does the Double Bass sound compared to music written for it?", "correct": "An octave", "incorrect": ["A fifth", "A fourth", "A sixth"]}, "183": {"question": "Which clef does the violin use?", "correct": "Treble", "incorrect": ["Alto", "Bass", "Tenor"]}, "184": {"question": "Which clef does the Double Bass use?", "correct": "Bass clef", "incorrect": ["Tenor Clef", "Alto Clef", "It uses both the tenor and bass clef"]}, "185": {"question": "What sort of place would 18th-century chamber music be played in?", "correct": "A small venue", "incorrect": ["A large concert hall", "Anywhere", "A garage"]}, "186": {"question": "How many players are there usually per part in chamber music?", "correct": "One", "incorrect": ["None", "Three", "Two"]}, "187": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the key of the first movement?", "correct": "Tonic", "incorrect": ["Dominant", "Supertonic", "Mediant"]}, "188": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the key of the second movement?", "correct": "Subdominant", "incorrect": ["Submediant", "Leading-note", "Tonic"]}, "189": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the key of the third movement?", "correct": "Tonic", "incorrect": ["Subdominant", "Dominant", "Supertonic"]}, "190": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the key of the fourth movement?", "correct": "Tonic", "incorrect": ["Leading-note", "Submediant", "Mediant"]}, "191": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the form of the first movement?", "correct": "Sonata Form", "incorrect": ["Minuet and Trio", "Ternary form", "Strophic Form"]}, "192": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the form of the second movement?", "correct": "Ternary form", "incorrect": ["Modified Stropic form", "Rondo Form", "Binary Form"]}, "193": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the form of the third movement?", "correct": "Minuet and Trio", "incorrect": ["Binary Form", "Through-composed form", "Sonata Form"]}, "194": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the form of the fourth movement?", "correct": "Sonata Form", "incorrect": ["Rondo Form", "Modified Strophic Form", "Ternary form"]}, "195": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the speed/tempo of the first movement?", "correct": "Allegro", "incorrect": ["Slow", "Moderate", "Very Fast"]}, "196": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the speed/tempo of the second movement?", "correct": "Slow", "incorrect": ["Allegro", "Very Fast", "Moderate"]}, "197": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the speed/tempo of the third movement?", "correct": "Moderate", "incorrect": ["Very Fast", "Allegro", "Slow"]}, "198": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the speed/tempo of the fourth movement?", "correct": "Very Fast", "incorrect": ["Moderate", "Slow", "Allegro"]}, "199": {"question": "What is the cello's full name?", "correct": "Violoncello", "incorrect": ["The full name of a cello", "Violincello", "Violacello"]}, "200": {"question": "What is a mute?", "correct": "A device attached to an instrument to change the tone of it or to reduce its volume", "incorrect": ["A button on a conferencing software which disables the microphone", "A device attached to an instrument to stop all sound that comes from it", "A device attached to an instrument while tuning which shows whether the instrument is sharp or flat"]}, "201": {"question": "What is it meant by 'col legno'?", "correct": "An instruction for string players to strike a string with the stick part of the bow", "incorrect": ["An instruction for string players to pluck the strings", "Cool Lego", "Quick and Lively"]}, "202": {"question": "'Pizzicato' is the musical term for what?", "correct": "Plucking the strings", "incorrect": ["With spirit", "Extremely fast staccato playing", "An instruction for string players to strike a string with the stick part of the bow"]}, "203": {"question": "What does 'Con Sordino' mean?", "correct": "To play with the mute", "incorrect": ["Without", "Pluck the strings", "Eat Sardines"]}, "204": {"question": "What is a peg on a stringed instrument used for?", "correct": "To tighten or loosen the string while tuning", "incorrect": ["To change the tone of the instrument", "To make a string thinner", "To reduce the volume of the instrument"]}, "205": {"question": "'Arco' is the Italian term for what?", "correct": "To play with the bow", "incorrect": ["To play on or near the bridge", "To play with the stick part of the bow", "Slow; leisurely"]}, "206": {"question": "What does 'Spiccato' mean?", "correct": "Extremely fast staccato playing", "incorrect": ["Extremely slow staccato playing", "Short and accented staccato", "Slackening speed"]}, "207": {"question": "What does 'Sul Ponticello' mean?", "correct": "To play on or near the bridge", "incorrect": ["Pluck the strings", "Play with a cello", "To play with the bow"]}, "208": {"question": "What is the rule for melodic minor scales?", "correct": "The 6th and 7th scale degrees are raised on the way up, and both are lowered on the way down", "incorrect": ["Raise the 7th scale degree on the way up, and lower it on the way down", "The 6th and 7th scale degrees are lowered on the way up, and both are raised on the way down", "Raise the 6th scale degree on the way up, and lower it on the way down"]}, "209": {"question": "When writing a lied, when should a minor key be used?", "correct": "When the topic of the poem is sad", "incorrect": ["When the topic of the poem is happy", "If the poem is about free food", "When the poem is in third-person"]}, "210": {"question": "In first inversion chords, which degree of the chord is held in the bass part?", "correct": "The third", "incorrect": ["The tonic", "The fifth", "The eighth"]}, "211": {"question": "In 4 part vocal arrangements, how far apart can the tenor and bass voices be?", "correct": "As far apart as they like, but they must stay within vocal range", "incorrect": ["An octave", "A 7th", "Two octaves"]}, "212": {"question": "In 4 part vocal arrangements, how far apart can the soprano and alto be?", "correct": "An octave", "incorrect": ["A 3rd", "As far apart as they like, but they must stay within vocal range", "A 6th"]}, "213": {"question": "In 4 part vocal arrangements, how far apart can the alto and tenor be?", "correct": "An octave", "incorrect": ["A fourth", "A fifth", "As far apart as they like, but they must stay within vocal range"]}, "214": {"question": "Which note is doubled in first inversion chords?", "correct": "The tonic", "incorrect": ["The fifth", "The third", "No note is doubled"]}, "215": {"question": "Which sort of beat should a I64 chord land on?", "correct": "Strong beat", "incorrect": ["Weak beat", "The second beat", "The off-beat"]}, "216": {"question": "Which note is doubled in I64 chords?", "correct": "The fifth", "incorrect": ["The tonic", "The second", "The third"]}, "217": {"question": "Which chord must follow a I64 chord?", "correct": "Chord V", "incorrect": ["Chord ii", "Chord I", "Chord vi"]}, "218": {"question": "In the tenor part of a I64 chord, what does the tonic go to?", "correct": "The leading note", "incorrect": ["The dominant", "The supertonic", "The third"]}, "219": {"question": "Which chord must V6 lead to?", "correct": "Chord I", "incorrect": ["Chord V", "Chord vii", "Chord IV"]}, "220": {"question": "In two-part writing, scale degree no. 3 will always represent which chord?", "correct": "I6", "incorrect": ["V", "IV", "vi"]}, "221": {"question": "In two-part writing, scale degree no. 5 will always represent which chord?", "correct": "V", "incorrect": ["IV", "ii", "ii6"]}, "222": {"question": "In two-part writing, if the 3rd of the chord is in the bass, which note should we try to use in the treble?", "correct": "The root", "incorrect": ["The fifth", "The seventh", "The third"]}}